Guide to the Charles T. Davis Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Charles T. Davis papers
1931-1980
JWJ MSS 91
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
29.67
(38 boxes)
The collection contains correspondence, research and teaching files, and personal papers documenting the life of American academic Charles T. Davis. Correspondents feature literary scholars and African-American artists, writers, and cultural figures, including Doris Alexander, Anthony Appiah, Amiri Baraka, Romare Bearden, John Blassingame, Michel Fabre, Leon Forrest, Athol Fugard, Henry Louis Gates, Leon Higginbotham, Ishmael Reed, Jean Toomer, and others. Correspondents also include colleagues and students. Research and Teaching Files contain files documenting Davis's professional activity as an academic at various institutions from the 1950s through 1970s. Research files include notes and subject files on 19th and 20th century writers and African-American history, literature, and culture. Teaching files include course and lecture notes, writings by Davis and others, and administrative files. Personal papers consists of various other materials, including family papers, audiovisual material, and military and academic records.
Davis, Charles T. (Charles Twitchell), 1918-1981
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Charles T. Davis, 2005.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Restricted material in boxes 34-37 are restricted until 2051.
Box 38 contains audiovisual material. Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Charles T. Davis (1918-1981)
Charles Twitchell Davis, born April 29, 1918, in Hampton, VA, was a literary critic and scholar. Davis was educated at Dartmouth College (1939), University of Chicago (1942), and New York University (1951), and taught at NYU (1948-1955), Princeton University (1955-1961), Penn State (1961-1970), University of Iowa (1970-1976) and finally Yale University (1972-1981), where he taught until his death in 1981.
Davis's early work was on American poetry of the 19th and early 20th centuries, but later in his career he began to focus more on black literature, culture, and history. His study of black American literature helped bring it to the fore as a significant part of the American literary tradition, and as a leader of the African-American studies program at Yale University, he was an important figure in the development of African-American studies in American universities. His books include Black is the Color of the Cosmos (1982) and The Slave's Narrative (1985).
Biographical information taken from "Charles T. Davis." Contemporary Black Biography. Vol. 48. Detroit: Gale, 2005. Gale Biography In Context. Web. 2 May 2012.
Scope and Contents
The Charles T. Davis papers contains correspondence, research and teaching files, and personal papers documenting the life of American academic Charles T. Davis. Correspondents feature literary scholars and African-American artists, writers, and cultural figures, including Doris Alexander, Kwame Anthony Appiah, Amiri Baraka, Romare Bearden, John Blassingame, Michel Fabre, Leon Forrest, Athol Fugard, Henry Louis Gates, Leon Higginbotham, Ishmael Reed, Jean Toomer, and others. Correspondents also include colleagues and students. Research and Teaching Files contain files documenting Davis's professional activity as an academic at various institutions from the 1950s through 1970s. Research files include notes and subject files on 19th and 20th century writers and African-American history, literature, and culture. Teaching files include course and lecture notes, writings by Davis and others, and administrative files. Personal papers consists of various other materials, including family papers, audiovisual material, and military and academic records.
Arrangement
Organized into three series: I. Correspondence, [circa 1930s-1980]. II. Research and Teaching Files, 1936-1980. III. Personal Papers, 1931-1980.
African Americans -- History; American literature -- African American authors; American literature -- 20th Century; Audiovisual materials; Sound recordings; Alexander, Doris; Appiah, Anthony, 1954-; Baraka, Amiri, 1934-2014; Bearden, Romare, 1911-1988; Blassingame, John W., 1940-2000; Davis, Charles T. (Charles Twitchell), 1918-1981; Fabre, Michel, 1933-2007; Forrest, Leon, 1937-1997; Fugard, Athol, 1932-; Gates, Henry Louis, Jr., 1950-; Higginbotham, A. Leon, Jr., 1928-1998; Reed, Ishmael, 1938-; Toomer, Jean, 1894-1967
- Correspondence, [circa 1930s-1980]; Series I; 8.42; (9 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Organized into two subseriesgroupings for Personal and Professional Correspondence.
  Scope and Contents
  Series I. features correspondence with literary scholars and African-American artists, writers, and cultural figures, including Doris Alexander, Anthony Appiah, Amiri Baraka, Romare Bearden, John Blassingame, Michel Fabre, Leon Forrest, Athol Fugard, Henry Louis Gates, Leon Higginbotham, Ishmael Reed, Jean Toomer, and others. Correspondents also include colleagues and students.
  Additional correspondence can be found in Series II-III.
  - Personal Correspondence
    - Personal correspondence, 17 (Box 1)
    - Personal correspondence (continued), 11 (Box 2)
    - Sympathy cards, 5 (Box 2)
    - Sympathy cards (continued), 19 (Box 3)
    - Sympathy cards (continued), 2 (Box 4)
  - Professional Correspondence
    - Aaboe, Asgar (Box 4)
    - Abrahams, Roger D. (Box 4)
    - Adams, Gleason (Box 4)
    - Adams, Ruth M. (Box 4)
    - Agyeman, Opoku (Box 4)
    - Allen, Gay (Box 4)
    - Alexander, Doris, 3 (Box 4)
      Includes letters from Lilika Marmaras, J.W. Abruquah, Edward Margolies, and Luisa De Vecchi Rocca
    - Alexander, Margaret Walker, 2 (Box 4)
    - Aliyu, A. Y. (Box 4)
    - American Labor History Series (Box 4)
    - Anderson, Elijah, 2 (Box 4)
    - Anozie, Sunday Ogbonna (Box 4)
    - Andrews, Dwight D. (Box 4)
    - Appiah, Anthony, 2 (Box 4)
    - Aptheker, Herbert (Box 4)
    - Ashton, Charlotte (Box 4)
    - Austin, Ramona (Box 4)
    - Baker, Houston A., Jr. (Box 4)
    - Ball, Jessie C. (Box 4)
    - Banik, Sheilea Eubanks (Box 4)
    - Baraka, Amiri (Box 4)
    - Barksdale, Richard K (Box 4)
    - Barth, John, 2 (Box 4)
    - Basic, Sonja (Box 4)
    - Bateson, F. W. (Box 4)
    - Bearden, Romare (Box 4)
    - Beckman, John (Box 4)
    - Bell, Michael Edward (Box 4)
    - Bell, Wendell (Box 4)
    - Benston, Kim (Box 4)
    - Badger, Anne (Box 4)
    - Bailey, LaTanya (Box 4)
    - Bercovitch, Sacvan (Box 4)
    - Betsky, Celia, 2 (Box 4)
    - Betsky, Seymour (Box 4)
    - Birt, Rodger C. (Box 4)
    - Blake, Eubie (Box 4)
    - Blassingame, John (Box 4)
    - Boone, Sylvia (empty folder) (Box 4)
    - Boone, Sylvia A. (Box 4)
    - Borden, John S. (Box 4)
    - Borman, Frank (Box 4)
    - Bouchet, Edward Alexander (Box 4)
    - Bowen, Ezra (Box 4)
    - Boyd, William L. (Box 4)
    - Bradford, Colin (Box 4)
    - Branch, William B. (Box 4)
    - Brault, Gerard J. (Box 4)
    - Brauner, Gary (Box 4)
    - Braxton, Joanne, 2 (Box 4)
    - Brodhead, Richard Halleck (Box 4)
    - Brown, Arvin (Box 4)
    - Brown, Clifton (Box 4)
    - Brown, Don (Box 4)
    - Brown, JoAnne (Box 4)
    - Brown, Lennox (Box 4)
    - Brown, Nina (Box 4)
    - Brown, Rae Linda (Box 4)
    - Brown, Sterling (Box 4)
    - Review: Yale University Press (Box 4)
    - Correspondence about positions for Blacks in universities & colleges (Box 4)
    - Toomer, Jean (Box 4)
    - Benston, Kimberly W. (Box 4)
    - Bonenberger, Geof (Box 4)
    - Brown, Win and Jane (Box 4)
    - Brustein, Robert (Box 4)
    - Kia Bunseki, Fu-Kiau (Box 4)
    - Busia, Apena P. A. (Box 4)
    - Byrd, Rudy (Box 4)
    - Calder, Angus (Box 4)
    - Calio, Louise (Box 4)
    - Carew, Jan (Box 4)
    - Carew, Jean (Box 4)
    - Carter, George E. (Box 4)
    - Celeste, Richard F. (Box 4)
    - Center for Independent Study (Box 4)
    - Chakrabarty, H. R. (Box 4)
    - Chestnut, Maria (Gourdin & Morrow) (Box 4)
    - Childs, John B. (Box 4)
    - Chirenje, J. Mutero (Box 4)
    - Christ-Janer, Victor (Box 4)
    - Clark, Kenneth (Box 4)
    - Presidents Pa & Iowa (Box 4)
    - Clark, Vèvè A. (Box 4)
    - Cohen, Oscar and Marge (Box 4)
    - Coles, Robert, A. (Box 4)
    - Colón, Alan (Box 4)
    - Cooke, Michael (Box 4)
    - Coulter, Cyrus J. (Box 4)
    - Corrigan, Robert (Box 4)
    - Covici, Pascal, Jr. (Box 4)
    - Cowan, Michael (Box 4)
    - Clare Crane's essay (Box 4)
    - Cronon, William J. (Box 4)
    - Crusto, Mitchell F. (Box 4)
    - Cunningham, George, 2 (Box 4)
    - Cameron, Kenneth (Box 4)
    - Clark, William Bedford (Box 4)
    - Clarke, Austin (Box 4)
    - Cunningham, George (Box 4)
    - Daheim, Luzia (Box 4)
    - Darnell, Michael (Box 4)
    - Davis, Arthur P. (Box 4)
    - Davis, Allison (Box 4)
    - Davis, Collis (Box 4)
    - Davis, John A. (Box 4)
    - Divine, Mother (Box 5)
    - Davis, Susan (Box 5)
    - Decca (Box 5)
    - deUriarte, Mercedes Lynn (Box 5)
    - Dejoie, Macletus M. (Box 5)
    - Demby, William (Box 5)
    - Diggs, Irene (Box 5)
    - Dihoff, Ivan R. (Box 5)
    - Djerassi, Ramy (Box 5)
    - Dixon, Melvin (Box 5)
    - Donaldson, William (Box 5)
    - Downey, John (empty folder) (Box 5)
    - Drake, St. Clair (Box 5)
    - Driskell, David (Box 5)
    - Duffy, Joseph (Box 5)
    - Dwyer, John Orr (Box 5)
    - Economic - Felder, Peck (Box 5)
    - Edel, Leon (Box 5)
    - Edelman, Marian Wright (Box 5)
    - Emil, David (Box 5)
    - Encyclopedia Africana, 2 (Box 5)
    - Endfield, Cy (Box 5)
    - Engle, Paul (Box 5)
    - Esahak, George (Box 5)
    - Everson, Mark W. (Box 5)
    - Fabre, Michel, 2 (Box 5)
    - Faghih, Nasrine (Box 5)
    - Fair, R. (Box 5)
    - Farnsworth - Ray Wright book (Box 5)
    - Farnsworth, Robert (Box 5)
    - Feinsilver, Julie (Box 5)
    - Fenn, John (Box 5)
    - Fernandez, Bethany (empty folder) (Box 5)
    - Ferris, William R. (Box 5)
    - Study of Southern Literature (Box 5)
    - Fischer, C. (Box 5)
    - Fiedler, Leslie, 2 (Box 5)
    - Figueroa, John S. (Box 5)
    - Fineberg, Jonathan (Box 5)
    - Fishkin, Shelley (Box 5)
    - Forrest, Leon (Box 5)
    - Frankenthaler, Helen (Box 5)
    - Franklin, Bruce (Box 5)
    - Franklin, Vincent (Box 5)
    - Fugard, Athol (Box 5)
    - Gaines, David (Box 5)
    - Garner, Stanton B., Sr. (Box 5)
    - Garrigues, Laura (Box 5)
    - Gates, Henry Louis, 3 (Box 5)
    - Garrow, David J. (Box 5)
    - Geffen, David (Box 5)
    - Gerber, John (Box 5)
    - Gephart, George W., Jr. (Box 5)
    - Giamatti, A. Barlett (Box 5)
    - Gelfant, Blanche H. (Box 5)
    - Gibson, Donald, 3 (Box 5)
    - Greene, Victor (Box 5)
    - Gilman, Sander (Box 5)
    - Ginsburg and Laughlin (Box 5)
    - Goldberg, Robert (Box 5)
    - Goldblatt, Stanford (Box 5)
    - Goldstein, Abraham S. (Box 5)
    - Goodman, William W. (Box 5)
    - Gordon, Edmund (Box 5)
    - Gorlier, Claudio (Box 5)
    - Goss, Clay (Box 5)
    - Graham, Sheila (Box 5)
    - Graves, Earl G. (Box 5)
    - Guare, John (Box 5)
    - Haizlip, Harold C. (Box 5)
    - Hamel, Mary (Box 5)
    - Hamilton, Charles (Box 5)
    - Hanson, Susan Atherton, 2 (Box 5)
    - Harper, Michael (Box 5)
    - Harris, Donald (Box 5)
    - Harris, Wilson, 2 (Box 5)
    - Harvey, William R. (Box 5)
    - The Edens, the Hollands (Box 5)
    - Hayden, Robert (Box 5)
    - Hayman, David (Box 5)
    - Hegel, Richard (Box 5)
    - Henderson, Mae Gwendolyn, 2 (Box 5)
    - Herbert, Eugenia Warren (Box 5)
    - Higginbotham, Leon, 2 (Box 5)
    - Hills, Carla (Box 5)
    - Hope Hog Farm Foundation (Box 5)
    - Holt, C. D. (Box 5)
    - Hudlin, Warrington (Box 5)
    - Hyatt, Donald B. (Box 5)
    - Hirsch, Ed (Box 5)
    - Inge, Thomas (Box 5)
    - Isaac, Ephraim (Box 5)
    - Jackson, Barbara (Box 5)
    - Jung-Kee, Lee (Box 5)
    - Juneja, Renu (Box 5)
    - Kaplan, Janice E. (Box 5)
    - Keeley, Edmund (Box 5)
    - Kennan, Elizabeth (Box 5)
    - Kent, Judith S. (Box 5)
    - Kern, Alex and Sean (Box 5)
    - King, Michael J. (Box 5)
    - Kinnamon, Kenneth (Box 5)
    - Klein, Suzanne (Box 5)
    - Kluger, Martin S. (Box 5)
    - Koenen, Anne (Box 5)
    - Kramer, Victor (Box 5)
    - Kochanek, Pat (Box 5)
    - Jackson, Blyden (Box 5)
    - Jackson, Daniel W. (Box 5)
    - Jackson, Henry F. (Box 6)
    - James, Charles L. (Box 6)
    - Jaynes, Gerald D. (Box 6)
    - Jewkes, Wilfred T. (Box 6)
    - Joans, Ted (Box 6)
    - Johnson, Hall (Box 6)
    - Johnson, Margaret (Box 6)
    - Johnson, Helen Armstead (Box 6)
    - Johnson, Teresa D. (Box 6)
    - Johnston, Judy (Box 6)
    - Jones, Gilbert (Box 6)
    - Jones, Jane (Box 6)
    - Jones, Julie S. (Box 6)
    - Johnston, Judy (Box 6)
    - Jones, David D., Jr. (Box 6)
    - Jones, Susan V. (Box 6)
    - Jordan, June (Box 6)
    - Joseph, George (Box 6)
    - Kroc, Ray A. (Box 6)
    - Kiah, Virginia J. (Box 6)
    - Kim, Yung-Chung (Box 6)
    - Kinnamon, Kenneth; Barksdale, Richard K. (Box 6)
    - Kleine, Susan (Box 6)
    - Krumholz, Harlan (Box 6)
    - Kubik, Gail (Box 6)
    - Lee, Mary Hope (Box 6)
    - LeParte, Pat, 3 (Box 6)
    - Lewis, Arthur, 2 (Box 6)
    - Lightfoot, Sara Lawrence (Box 6)
    - Lind, Ilse (Box 6)
    - Litz, A. Walton (Box 6)
    - Logan, Rayford W. (Box 6)
    - LaBrie, Henry G. (Box 6)
    - Landin, Joseph (Box 6)
    - Landau, Martin (Box 6)
    - Lang, Serge (Box 6)
    - Lapham, Lewis (Box 6)
    - Latham, A. J. H. (Box 6)
    - Latortue, Régine, 2 (Box 6)
    - Lauter, Paul (Box 6)
    - Forrest, Leon (Box 6)
    - Logue, Frank (Box 6)
    - Lowance, Mason (Box 6)
    - Leung, Felix (Box 6)
    - Lewis, Myran E. (Box 6)
    - Lind, Ilse (Box 6)
    - Luedtke, Luther (Box 6)
    - Lumley, J - Weintraub, Stanley (Box 6)
    - Major, Clarence (Box 6)
    - McAlpine, Theresa (Box 6)
    - McIntosh, James H. (Box 6)
    - McHenry, Mary (Box 6)
    - Miller, James (Box 6)
    - Meade, Matthew (Box 6)
    - Meyer, Michael (Box 6)
    - Murphy, Dale (Box 6)
    - Moses, Wilson (Box 6)
    - Moynahan, Julian (Box 6)
    - Land, Mary (Box 6)
    - McClane, Kenneth, Jr. (Box 6)
    - McLaughlin, Sally (Box 6)
    - McCree, Wade H. (Box 6)
    - McHenry, Mary W. (Box 6)
    - McFadden, Mike (Box 6)
    - McKay, Charlie (Box 6)
    - Makinde, M. A. (Box 6)
    - Marks, Linda (Box 6)
    - Marks, Merton (Box 6)
    - Marrett, Eugene E. (Box 6)
    - Mohr, Clarence L. (Box 6)
    - Moon, Henry Lee (Box 6)
    - Morrisey, John Carroll (Box 6)
    - Morrison, Steve (Box 6)
    - Morrison, Toni (Box 6)
    - Morrow, Edward (Box 6)
    - Morse, Charlotte C. (Box 6)
    - Moses, Wilson, 2 (Box 6)
    - Marmor, Theodore R. (Box 6)
    - Martin, Jennifer (Box 6)
    - Martin, Stephen H. (Box 6)
    - Marx, Gary T. (Box 6)
    - Matshoba, Mtutuzel (Box 6)
    - Matthews, George C. (Box 6)
    - Mead, Chris (Box 6)
    - McClane, Ken, Jr. (Box 6)
    - McGuire, James Joseph (Box 6)
    - McKee, Elmore M. (Box 6)
    - Mehrotra, Arvind Krishna (Box 6)
    - Meier, August (Box 6)
    - Mendelson, Edward (Box 6)
    - Mero, Harrison H. (Box 6)
    - Merriman, John (Box 6)
    - Mitford, Jessica (Decca) (Box 6)
    - Michele, Grace M. (Box 6)
    - Miller, Arthur (Box 6)
    - Miller, G. William (Box 6)
    - Molette, Carlton W. (Box 6)
    - Mosher, Gregory (Box 6)
    - Motley, Constance B. (Box 6)
    - Mottl, Tahi (Box 6)
    - Moynahan, Julian (Box 6)
    - Murray, Albert (Box 6)
    - Nagan, Winston (Box 6)
    - Nagel, James (Box 6)
    - Newman, Paul (Box 6)
    - Nagel, James E. (Box 6)
    - Napier, Davie (Box 6)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities (Box 6)
    - Nazareth, Peter (Box 6)
    - Neil, Jim (Box 7)
    - Nelson, Patricia (Box 7)
    - Ney, Edward (Box 7)
    - Neussendorfer, Margaret (Box 7)
    - Nkondo, G. M. (Box 7)
    - Nunes, Maria Luisa (Box 7)
    - Oates, John F. (Box 7)
    - O'Meally, Robert G. (Box 7)
    - Orr, Linda (Box 7)
    - Osborne, J. M. (Box 7)
    - Painter, Nell Irvin (Box 7)
    - Palmer, Robert (Box 7)
    - Papp, Joseph (Box 7)
    - Paredes, Raymund (Box 7)
    - Patterson, Eric (Box 7)
    - Storandt, Peter (Box 7)
    - Szwed, John F. (Box 7)
    - Patterson, Eric (Box 7)
    - Paulson, Barbara (Box 7)
    - Payne, Deborah (Box 7)
    - Pearson, Malcolm (Box 7)
    - Perry, Lewis and Elisabeth (Box 7)
    - Trinkaus on Branford, etc. (Box 7)
    - Taylor, Dalmas (Box 7)
    - Pelcynski, Z. (Box 7)
    - Pelton, Lee (Box 7)
    - Penney, Sharon H. (Box 7)
    - Post, Penny (Box 7)
    - Penney, Sherry (Box 7)
    - Perkoff, Gerald T. (Box 7)
    - Perlis, Vivian (Box 7)
    - Poeymirou, Frank (Box 7)
    - Porter, Horace, 2 (Box 7)
    - Price, Andrew, Jr. (Box 7)
    - Price, Derek and Ellen (Box 7)
    - Raboteau, Albert J. (Box 7)
    - Reed, Ishmael, 2 (Box 7)
    - Rampersad, Arnold (Box 7)
    - Reilly, Sean (Box 7)
    - Reinhardt, Rochelle M. (Box 7)
    - Rao, K. S. Narayana (Box 7)
    - Rose, Mark (Box 7)
    - Richards, Denby (Box 7)
    - Richards, Lloyd (Box 7)
    - Richlin, Amy (Box 7)
    - Ripley, Peter (Box 7)
    - Rivkin, David W. (Box 7)
    - Robinson, Willie C. (Box 7)
    - Rockefeller, David (Box 7)
    - Rodgers, Audrey (Box 7)
    - Rose, Peter I. (Box 7)
    - Rosens - Franks (Box 7)
    - Ryan, Dorothy (Box 7)
    - Sanchez, Sonia (Box 7)
    - Walton, Ortiz Montaigne (Box 7)
    - St. John, Mary Macarthur (Box 7)
    - Sacks, Kate (Box 7)
    - St. Clair, Peter (Box 7)
    - Sams, Henry (Box 7)
    - Schorr, Beth Susan (Box 7)
    - Scott, Larry (Box 7)
    - Senghor, Leopold (Box 7)
    - Serafine, Mary Louise (Box 7)
    - Sharpe, Bruce R. (Box 7)
    - Sharpe, Patricia L., 2 (Box 7)
    - Silk, Ed (Box 7)
    - Simpson, Lorenzo C. (Box 7)
    - Singer, Maxine (Box 7)
    - Sinha, Pramila (Box 7)
    - Skerrett, Joseph (Box 7)
    - Skerrett, Joseph T., Jr. (Box 7)
    - Slie, Samuel N. (Box 7)
    - Smith, Henry Nash (Box 7)
    - Sommer, Miriam Goldstein (Box 7)
    - Smith, Jim and Terrie (Box 7)
    - Smith, Jessie C. (Box 7)
    - Smith, M. G. (Box 7)
    - Snyder, Susan (Box 7)
    - Smith, Sidonie (Box 7)
    - Snead, S. (Box 7)
    - Snowden, Frank M., Jr. (Box 7)
    - Snowden, Muriel (Box 7)
    - Soyinka, Wole (Box 7)
    - Staros, Patricia (Box 7)
    - Stepto, Robert (Box 7)
    - Stewart, Jeffrey C. (Box 7)
    - Conference on Minority Groups and the Study of Languages and Literatures, MLA (Box 7)
    - Stone, Chuck (Box 7)
    - Stone, I. F. (Box 7)
    - Theodore, Eustace (Box 7)
    - Thorburn, David (Box 7)
    - Thornton, Virginius B. (Box 7)
    - Trahern, Joseph B., Jr. (Box 7)
    - Traylor, Steve (Box 7)
    - Turner, Arlin (Box 7)
    - Valenti, Fernando Miguel (Box 7)
    - Van Doren, Charles (Box 7)
    - Von Hoene, Bill (Box 7)
    - Waite, William Gilman (Box 7)
    - Walcott, Derek (Box 7)
    - West, Paul (Box 7)
    - Walker, Henry (Box 7)
    - Warnke, Frank (Box 7)
    - Waters, Ronald S. (Box 7)
    - Weaver, Harold D., Jr. (Box 7)
    - Weaver, Robert (Box 7)
    - Welty, Eudora, 2 (Box 7)
    - Wortheimer, Laura (Box 7)
    - Wesleyan Program (Box 7)
    - Wertheim, S. (Box 7)
    - Westby, D. (Box 7)
    - White, Philip (Box 7)
    - Whitman, Daniel, 2 (Box 7)
    - Whitman, Jon (Box 7)
    - Wilhelm, Robert (Box 7)
    - Wilcove, David (Box 7)
    - Williams, Andrea (Box 7)
    - Williams, Sherley Anne (Box 7)
    - Williams, Wilburn (Box 7)
    - Williams, Wilburn (continued) (Box 8)
    - Willis, Susan (Box 8)
    - Wilson, William J. (Box 8)
    - Wolf, Merrill (Box 8)
    - Woodard, Fredrick (Box 8)
    - Wright, Patricia A. (Box 8)
    - Wriston, Walter B. (Box 8)
    - Yeager, Robert (Box 8)
    - Yellin, Sean (Box 8)
    - Young, Al (Box 8)
    - Young, Jesse A. (Box 8)
    - Young, Philip (Box 8)
    - Zeiger, Arthur and Melissa (Box 8)
    - Zinsser, William (Box 8)
    - Personal and professional correspondence, 3 (Box 9)
    - Sachs, Kate (Box 9)
    - Schlissel, Lillian (Box 9)
    - Scott, Nathan (Box 9)
    - Sembene, Ousmane (Box 9)
    - Shoemaker, Brant (Box 9)
    - Singh, Amritjit (Box 9)
    - Sloan, Philip (Box 9)
    - Smith, James (Box 9)
    - Smith, Leo (Box 9)
    - Smith, Ware (Box 9)
    - Smith, W. R. (Box 9)
    - Snowden, F. M. (Box 9)
    - Stanley, Eric (Box 9)
    - Stewart, Jeffrey (Box 9)
    - Stout, Sandy (Box 9)
    - Vincent, Theophilus (Box 9)
    - Waitzkin, Stella (Box 9)
    - Williams, Cecil B. (Box 9)
    - Yellin, Jean Fagan (Box 9)
    - Zavadil, J. B. (Box 9)
    - Recommendations, 1974 (Box 9)
    - Army letter (Box 9)
- Research and Teaching Files, 1936-1980; Series II; 14.87; (18 boxes)
  Materials arranged as received by the library.
  Series II. Research and Teaching Files contains files documenting Davis's professional activity as an academic at various institutions from the 1950s through 1970s. Research files include notes and subject files on 19th and 20th century writers and African-American literature, culture, and history. Teaching files include course and lecture notes, writings by Davis and others, and administrative files.
  Folder headings transcribed.
  - Notebooks, 5 (Box 9)
  - Notebooks (continued), 8 (Box 10)
  - The Italian University - A Talk (Box 11)
  - Introduction of Sidney Hook, 1971 February 17 (Box 11)
  - Honors convocation, 1972 May 6 (Box 11)
  - University of Massachusetts file (Box 11)
  - Speech for Alumni (Box 11)
  - Columbia University (Box 11)
  - Offers: 1. Northern Illinois University, 2. California State College at San Bernardino, 3. Lecture at University of Kansas (Box 11)
  - Harvard University, Summer School (Box 11)
  - University of Buffalo - Provost & Department of English (Box 11)
  - Review: The Nation (Box 11)
  - Speech for entering freshman, 1980 (Box 11)
  - State University of New York, Stony Brook (Box 11)
  - Wine list: Mayberry (Box 11)
  - Humanistic Imperatives in an Age of Technology (Box 11)
  - Printed material (Box 11)
  - Personal correspondence (Box 11)
  - Photographs: Family (Box 11)
  - Mail for A. C. & C. C. Davis (Box 11)
    Includes Proposal for Use of Black Center: A Center for Black Music
  - National Endowment for the Humanities - Summer seminars (Box 11)
  - Herald Tribune Book Review, 1961 January 15 (Box 11)
  - New York Times Book Review, 1969 May 18 (Box 11)
  - Auden (Box 11)
  - Lectures on Contemporary Literature in India (Box 11)
  - English Romantic Poets (Box 11)
  - Materials on the English Romantic Poets (Box 11)
  - Class notes: The Greeks, Antigone, Greek science (Box 11)
  - Dostoyevsky & Mann: comment on the Primavera (Box 11)
  - Appreciation, 1979 (Box 11)
  - Yale Afro-American Bibliographies and Indexes (Box 11)
  - Unsorted correspondence (Box 11)
  - Writings by others (Box 11)
  - Professional correspondence (Box 11)
  - Burch lecture, Howard University (Box 11)
  - Literary Geography (Box 11)
  - Disruption at Penn State (Box 11)
  - Correspondence & recommendations, University of Iowa, 1972 (Box 11)
  - Dissertation: Robinson, Moody, MacKaye, Torrence (Box 11)
  - Speeches, 1969 (Box 11)
  - Whitman transcription of an unpublished letter (Box 11)
  - Notebooks, 2 (Box 12)
  - Notes (Box 12)
  - A Child's Christmas by Richard Bagley (Box 12)
  - The Religious Unity in the Works of Wm. Faulkner; Honors Thesis of Stanley E. Miller (Box 12)
  - 7 poems by Lewis Fleischner (Box 12)
  - 7 poems by Paul Oppenheimer (Box 12)
  - The Development of John Dos Passos; Senior Thesis by Marilyn Apter (Box 12)
  - The Nightingale Kingdom by Richard Bagley (Box 12)
  - Speech delivered by representative Adam C. Powell at Princeton University before: The American Cliosophic Society, 1960 May 2 (Box 12)
  - Poetry and fiction of students & reproduced verse (Box 12)
  - Notes on art and government (Box 12)
  - Notes
  - Eberhart - Verse play & lecture (Box 12)
  - Lowenthal, Rodger D.